It looked like the perfect bank robbery. But you
can’t judge a crime by its cover.
Inside Man is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Spike Lee.
When an armed, masked gang enter a Manhattan bank, lock the doors and take hostages, the detective assigned
to effect their release enters negotiations preoccupied with corruption charges he is facing.
Keith Frazier, played by Denzel Washington.
Dalton Russell, played by Clive Owen.
Madeleine White, played by Jodie Foster.
Arthur Case, played by Christopher Plummer.
John Darius, played by Willem Dafoe.
Bill Mitchell, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Inside Man is a 2006 American crime thriller film directed
by Spike Lee and written by Russell Gewirtz.
It centers on an elaborate bank heist-turned-hostage situation on Wall Street.
The film stars Denzel Washington as Detective Keith Frazier, the NYPD's hostage negotiator, Clive Owen as Dalton Russell, the mastermind who orchestrates the heist, and Jodie Foster as Madeleine
White, a Manhattan fixer who becomes involved at the request of the bank's founder Arthur Case (Christopher Plummer) to keep something in his safe deposit box protected from the robbers.
Gewirtz spent five years developing the premise before working
on what became his first original screenplay.
After he completed the script in 2002, Imagine Entertainment purchased it to be made by
Universal Pictures, with Imagine co-founder Ron Howard attached to direct.
After Howard stepped down, his business partner Brian Grazer began
looking for a new director and ultimately hired Lee.
Principal photography took place on location in New
York City from June to August 2005.
With a $45–60 million budget, it is Lee's most expensive film.
Inside Man premiered in New York on March 20, 2006, and was released by
Universal Pictures across the United States four days later.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
$184.4 million, becoming Lee's highest-grossing film.
The film explores themes of new york city, hostage,
ultimatum, heist, police detective.
The tone is emotional and intense.